dometic.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Notice | Dometic

Dometic Group AB (publ) (“Dometic” or “we”) respects your privacy and protects the personal data we process about you. All processing of personal data is made in accordance with the GDPR. The following describes how we collect, process and share your personal data when you use and visit our websites (“Sites”).

WHAT PERSONAL DATA WILL BE PROCESSED?

You are free to explore our Sites without providing any personal data about yourself. However, all data (for example, your name, gender, address, telephone number or e-mail address) that indirectly or directly identifies you (“personal data”) and which you share with us via our Sites (or otherwise communicate to Dometic) will be managed in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

If you are using Dometic business websites, online order services or connected devices we may collect additional information from you. The types of data we collect directly from you includes the following: 

  * name, address, telephone number and email address (and company name, company address, company contact information, and other company details if you are using a Dometic business website or product);
  * log-in credentials, if you create a Dometic account;
  * billing information, such as shipping address, credit or debit card number, verification number, and expiration date;
  * information about purchases or other transactions with Dometic;
  * information about your customer service and maintenance interactions with Dometic;
  * information you choose to attribute in connection with your devices; and/or
  * any other information you choose to directly provide to Dometic in connection with your use of the Sites.

When you use the Sites we also collect certain information through automated means, sometimes with the help of third-party companies working on our behalf, using a variety of technologies, including cookies and similar tools. We collect and analyze information such as your IP address, browser types, browser language, operating system, the state or country from which you accessed the services, software and hardware attributes (including device IDs) referring and exit pages and URLs, platform type, the number of clicks, files you download, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the terms you use in searches on our sites, the date and time you used the relevant Site and upload or post content, error logs, and other similar information.

When you “like” or “follow” Dometic on Facebook, Instagram, YouTube or other social media sites, we may collect some information from you including your name, email address, and any comments or content you post relevant to Dometic. We also collect your information if you sign up for one of our promotions or submit information to us through social media sites. When using social media share-links, social plugins or similar on dometic.com, the respective social media platform will be able to notice your visit on the Dometic sites.

This Sites also contain so-called cookies. If you would like to receive more information about our collection of cookies, please read our Cookie Notice.

The Sites contain links to other websites. For the avoidance of doubt, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

WHAT IS THE PURPOSE OF PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

The processing of your personal data is necessary for the following:

  1. developing and improving Dometic’s website, i.e. by analysing your behaviour on the Sites (on an aggregated level); 
  2. communication purposes, e.g. when you sign up for Dometic’s newsletters or ask questions about Dometic products and services; 
  3. processing online orders;
  4. account and product registration and administration of your account; 
  5. process participation in Dometic sweepstakes, contests, or research; and
  6. processing product reviews that you submit about the Sites and Dometic products.

WHAT IS THE LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

The processing of your personal data for purpose (i) as listed in the section above is based on our legitimate interest in improving our website.

The processing of your personal data for purpose (ii)-(vi) as listed in the section above is based on the fact that the processing is necessary for us to fulfil the services requested by you, like managing an order, publishing a product review or receiving a newsletter.

The processing of your personal data for purpose (iii) as listed in the section above is based on the fact that we are under legal obligation to process your personal data as part of accounting and book-keeping regulations.

WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data against loss or unlawful access etc. The number of persons with access to your personal data is limited. Only individuals associated with Dometic that need to process your personal data in accordance with the purposes above will have access to your personal data.

Dometic will share your personal data with third parties if it is necessary so we can fulfil a statutory obligation, comply with a decision of a public authority or a court of law.

Also, Dometic will share your name, e-mail address and/or postal address with third parties in order to fulfill your request. On our behalf, they will provide you with the information or products in which you have expressed an interest.

Moreover, we will share your personal data with companies within the Dometic group of companies for the purpose of deliver products and services to you, ensure a consistent level of service across our products and services, and enhance our products, services, and your customer experience. When you submit a form requesting information or signing up for a newsletter, the information you submit will end up in a few limited email inboxes attended by resources allocated to serve your specific inquires.

We will also share your personal data with suppliers and partners that carry out services on our behalf such as billing, sales, marketing, product content, advertising, analytics, research, customer service, shipping and fulfilment, data storage, security, fraud prevention, payment processing, and legal services. 

Your personal data will be transferred to a country outside of EU/EEA such as the USA which may have a lower level of protection than within the EU/EEA. The transfer is needed to fulfil newsletter email deliveries, marketing, product content, advertising, analytics, research, customer service, shipping and fulfilment, data storage, security, fraud prevention and payment processing. The companies in the USA to which personal data will be transferred are all Privacy Shield certified.

FOR HOW LONG IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA STORED

We will keep your information for not longer than necessary for the purposes for which it is processed. The length of time for which we retain information depends on the purposes for which we collected and use it and/or as required to comply with applicable laws, rules and regulations.

WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS

Dometic Group AB (publ), reg. no. 556829-4390, address Hemvärnsgatan 15, SE-171 54 Solna, Sweden, is the controller of the processing of your personal data. This means that we are responsible for your personal data being processed correctly and in accordance with applicable laws. However, if you live in the United States, Latin America, or Canada, Dometic Corporation, address 1120 North Main Street, Elkhart, IN 46514, USA, is the controller of the processing of your personal data and is thus responsible for your personal data being processed correctly and in accordance with applicable laws. Dometic’s Data Protection Officer can be contacted at [privacy@dometic.com](mailto:privacy@dometic.com?subject=E-mail%20from%20dometi.com%20privacy%20policy%20page "E-mail Dometic Data Protection Officer").

Subject to any legal preconditions, the applicability of which have to be assessed in each individual case, you have the rights as follows. You are entitled to know what personal data we are processing regarding you, and you can request a copy of such data. You are entitled to have incorrect personal data regarding you corrected, and in some cases you may request that we delete your personal data (if, for example, the personal data is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected). You also have the right to object to certain processing of your personal data, and request that the processing of your personal data be limited. Please note that limitation or deletion of your personal data may result in us not being able to fulfil our commitments. You are also entitled to an extract of the personal data which you have provided to us in a machine-readable format and to transfer the personal data to another controller.

If you have any objections or complaints with the way we process your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant data protection supervisory authority.
